# **KELLY ALCINAY**

Reaistered Nurse



#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

New Graduate Registered Nurse, pending license with 11 years of extensive experience in the delivery of patient-centered and quality health care. Endowed with vast idea in providing daily living and personal care services to critically ill, disabled or cognitively impaired patients in accordance with an established care plan. Known for excellent clinical skills, ability to remain calm under pressure, aptitude to make swift and accurate decisions in emergency situations. Driven with the keen interest of saving live through proven skills in prioritizing medical care and problem-solving. Acknowledged with the ability to stay composed and intervene during crises, facilitate groups and collaborate on emergency healthcare teams. Proficient in assessing patients and developing individualized care plans towards carrying out nursing procedures appropriately. Physically strong with a high-level of patience and effective communication skills as well as excellent documentation, time-management, and management skills.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Medical terminology
- Scheduling
- Case Management
- Patient/Family education
- Effective communication
- Critical care nursing
- Wound cultures
- Cultural Awareness
- Strong Work ethics
- Phone triage
- Administration of injections
- Handling pressure
- Attention to details
- Insurance verification
- Lab specimen collection and preparation
- EMR computerized charting
- Leadership & training
- Patient discretion
- Customer service
- Excellent communication skills

## **CERTIFICATIONS**



- Registered Nurse
- Licensed Practical Nurse
- Infusion Care Experts IV Certification
- American Heart Association CPR/BLS Certification
- Parental Nutrition Certification

Pending

Aug 2019

Jun 2019

Aug 2020 - Aug 2022

Jun 2019

## **EDUCATION**

Registered Nurse

JFK Muhlenberg School of Nursing-Plainfield, NJ

2022

2019

**Practical Nursing** 

#### Lincoln Technical Institute- Iselin, NJ

- 3.7 GPA
- Made the Dean's list 3 times

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Licensed Practical Nurse

# Staffing the Universe AT Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ

December 2020 – August 2021

Triage Licensed Practical Nurse collaborating with physicians, nursing staff, and other members of the healthcare team focused on providing thorough care to Rutgers Health patients

Core Responsibilities & Accomplishments:

- Answer all clinical phone calls, communicate procedures and treatments to patient to gain cooperation, understanding and allay apprehension
- Contacted pharmacies for prescription renewals for patients
- Review plan of care, meds/tests with physicians as needed
- Documented all nursing history and assessment for patients in their charts
- Maintain proficiency in electronic medical records for documentation
- Documented all patient correspondence and correspondence with other pertinent health care providers
- Administered prescribed medications, teach patients how to administer injectable medication within the NJ Board of Nursing scope of practice
- Help obtain precertification/authorization with insurance companies prescribed medications or procedures
- Fill out school forms, DCP&P forms, Social Security Forms, write letters, reviews orders from home care/nursing agencies with physicians
- Participated in department and unit quality improvement activities
- Respond to life saving situations based upon nursing standards, policies, procedures and protocol
- Followed the Rutgers compliance standards as they appear in Rutgers Corporate Compliance Policy, Code of Conduct and Conflict of Interest Policy

## CFG Health Network at Union County Jail, Elizabeth, NJ

July 2020 – February 2020

Deliver care to inmate patients utilizing the nursing assessment protocols in assessment, planning, intervention, implementation, and evaluation in accordance with established CFG Health Network philosophy.

Core Responsibilities & Accomplishments:

- Perform and document medical evaluations on inmate patients consistent with the National Commission on Correctional Health Care (NCCHC) standards of care, NJ 10-A, American Correctional Association (ACA) and Performance Based National Detention Standards (PBNDS) as appropriate.
- Performed completed assessments of inmate patients in a variety of settings within the facility
- Ensure Medical Record documentation is in SOAP format
- Collaborate with primary care providers and other health care providers to ensure continuity, timeliness and appropriateness of care to inmate patients
- Record all care information legibly, concisely, accurately, and completely, in the appropriate format and on the appropriate forms, in a timely manner and signed
- Report reactions to treatments and medications, as well as changes in the inmates' emotional or physical condition
- Promote a therapeutic environment to ensure inmates are treated in a professional, ethical, and tactful manner
- Provide inmate patient education and/or discharge planning
- Perform other position-related duties as assigned

#### Licensed Practical Nurse

## ARISTACARE AT NORWOOD TERRACE- Plainfield, NJ

August 2019 - April 2020

Engaged actively in managing patients care according to each patient needs, also Review the Nursing Care Plan reflecting physical, emotional, restorative, rehabilitative, teaching, and goals for the resident doctor.

Core Responsibilities & Accomplishments:

- Integrate the Nursing Plan with the medical care prescribed
- Admitting new residents
- Assisting physicians during rounds of residents' rooms
- Assigning and delegating duties to non-licensed nursing staff
- Performing ongoing assessments of residents' physical and mental health
- Explaining procedures and treatment protocols to residents
- Planning and managing patient care according to each patient's needs
- Interviewing patients and recording their medical history
- Administer medication, including some injections, monitor medication doses and patient response
- Monitoring resident care and supervising other nursing staff
- Change bandages, dressings, and feeding tubes as needed; insert and change catheters
- Provide emotional support to patients and patients' families; listen to concerns and feedback
- Verifying that patient charts are updated promptly and accurately
- Assist and direct CNAs in organization and completion of workload to meet the needs of the residents, including but not limited to lifting, transferring, repositioning, etc.
- Observing and recording patients' conditions and reactions to medications and treatments
- Report any unusual or drastic changes in patient behavior/symptoms; seek help from superiors when needed
- Follow state and federal mandated standards and procedures

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request



